Diego Machado de Lima

Software Developer & Designer

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (+55 21) 99236-7700 diegomac@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I'm a jack of all trades. Computer scientist from UFRJ university and self-taught designer. Have been studying and working with computers since 2004.

Making games from start to finish is what really motivates me, contributing to it's design, art and everything else. I'm at my best creating game mechanics and I really enjoy creating UI interactions.

EXPERIENCE

<u>Gazeus Games</u> - Senior Mobile Game Developer

AUGUST 2016 - PRESENT

Yatzy Party

 Working on a Unity remake of the original Gazeus's Yatzy Party, adding new meta-game systems like collectables, IAP's and social features. Ported synchronous matches to asynchronous and added a FTUE with the Tutorial.

Dominoes Battle / Dominoes Remake

- Recreated the original Gazeus' Dominoes, a 4-year-old codebase game, for the Facebook's Instant Game platform using a in-house HTML5 tech stack.
- Remade the whole game from scratch, building a bigger and better native version using Unity
- Responsible for the tiles positioning algorithm and overall UI interactions.

Infinity Crystals

Created a minimalist match-3 game in Unity, integrated with the mobile e-sports <u>Skillz</u> platform.

MMA Federation

- Client maintenance in Unity: Added new training gyms, teams, fighters and cosmetic shop items. Added ads networks integrations, rewarded videos, new IAP's and implemented GameAnalytics.
- Server maintenance in Node.js: Created new tournaments, leagues and importing user data from legacy Redis and MongoDB databases.

Sabbatical Year - Solo Game Developer

JANUARY 2015 - AUGUST 2016

- <u>Darkness! Flashes!</u>, a 4-Player Deathmatch party game developed in 2 Months for AGBIC 2015 Game Jam. Developed using <u>Haxe</u> and <u>Haxeflixel</u>.
- <u>FisicaMente</u>, a puzzle-physics based game, aimed to children and teenagers to teach the
 basic concepts of physics, publishing it to Google Play and App Store. Won the second
 place at Federal Ministry of Communications's INOVApps Competition. Developed with
 Unity.

Radix Engenharia, Rio de Janeiro - Team Lead and Web Developer

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JANUARY 2015

Critical Studio, Rio de Janeiro - Game Developer

JANUARY 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2013

- Worked on <u>Dungeonland</u>, one of the biggest brazilian indie games, hitting Steam's Top-3 sellers on launch week.
- Built new enemies and their artificial intelligences and created new spells and attacks.
- Lots of bugfixing.
- Helped with Agile Implementation and Monitoring.
- Developed using Unity.

Igluu, Rio de Janeiro - Web Developer Intern

JULY 2012 - JANUARY 2013

EDUCATION

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro - Bachelor, Computer Science

SOCIAL

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/diegomac/

LANGUAGE

Brazilian Portuguese - IRL Level 5: Native or bilingual proficiency

English - IRL Level 3: Professional working proficiency